etrade.com.au 2009-10-23

# E*TRADE Australia | Online Share Trading

| **We Respect Your Privacy**  
---  
   
ETRADE Australia Limited and ETRADE Australia Securities Limited (collectively described as **E*TRADE** ) respect the privacy of all our customers and business contacts, and are committed to safeguarding the personal information that you provide to us.   
E*TRADE is subject to the National Privacy Principles ( **NPPs** ), which are contained in the _Privacy Act_ 1988 ( **Privacy Act** ). The NPPs govern how organisations must handle personal information.   
As E*TRADE may collect personal information about you online through our website, this Privacy Policy also outlines our approach to online privacy issues (at clause 6 below). Please read this Privacy Policy carefully as usage of our website is conditional upon you agreeing to be bound by it.   
   
The E*TRADE Privacy Policy is organised into the following sections: 

  1. What Personal Information Does E*TRADE Collect?
  2. How is Personal Information Used?
  3. Will Personal Information be Given to Anyone Else?
  4. Security of Personal Information
  5. Access and Correction
  6. Online Privacy Issues
  7. Business Contact Information
  8. How to Contact E*TRADE
  9. Changes to this Privacy Policy and Additional Information

This Privacy Policy has been prepared primarily for our customers and potential customers, who may have questions about how we handle personal information. However, E*TRADE may also handle information about people who are E*TRADE’s “business contacts”. E*TRADE’s handling of personal information about business contacts is discussed at clause 7.   
Back to Top  
**1\. What Personal Information Does E*TRADE Collect?**  
E*TRADE is an online financial services company that offers a combination of innovative value-added services through the use of leading-edge technology. We provide easy access to a secure, personalised trading environment.   
In the course of providing our products and service to you, E*TRADE may collect personal information about you. Personal information is information or opinion about an individual whose identity is apparent, or can reasonably be determined, from the information or opinion.   
The types of personal information that E*TRADE collects will depend on the nature of your dealings with us. E*TRADE collects personal information from:   
* **Our customers**  
E*TRADE may collect personal information about you when you become an E*TRADE shareholder, when you open an account with us or if you apply for a margin loan. This personal information we collect will include your name and address, and if you open an account with us, other contact details, the name of your bank and your bank account number and your tax file number (if you choose to provide it to us). As outlined at clause 2, E*TRADE needs this information in order to provide customers with its products and services. E*TRADE may collect other personal information from you (eg date of birth and occupation) in order to help E*TRADE establish whether you may need assistance to understand how to use our trading systems.   
* **Potential customers**  
If you request information from E*TRADE (eg by using the E*TRADE website or call centre), we may collect your contact details, including your name, postal and email addresses and your telephone and fax numbers.   
* **Business Contacts**  
E*TRADE may collect contact information from people with whom it does business (eg contact people in regulatory bodies, external service providers and the investment industry). If you are a “business contact” of E*TRADE, we may collect business contact information about you including your name, your position and the organisation you work for, your business telephone and fax number and your email address. As noted above, E*TRADE’s handling of business contact information is discussed at clause 7.   
E*TRADE only collects personal information if it is needed for the business purposes described in this privacy policy.   
Back to Top  
**2\. How is Personal Information Used?**  
If you are a customer, the personal information collected about you by E*TRADE is used for the purposes of establishing, administering, operating and maintaining your account with us. In addition, sometimes we will use personal information to establish a bank account for settlements relating to your E*TRADE trading account, and to create a CHESS Holder Identification Number. This will be explained in the terms and conditions you agree to when you open an account.   
If we don’t collect personal information from you, we will not be able to provide our products and services to you, or provide you with other information you have requested.   
From time to time we may also use personal information about customers and potential customers to inform you about E*TRADE products, services or promotions. If at any time you no longer wish to be notified about new E*TRADE products, services or promotions, please let us know. Our contact details are set out in clause 8 of this Privacy Policy.   
Back to Top  
**3\. Will Personal Information be Given to Anyone Else?**  
Personal information may be disclosed by E*TRADE in the following circumstances:  
* **For account-related purposes**  
If you are a customer, E*TRADE may disclose personal information about you to credit reporting agencies (with your consent), debt collecting agencies and payment system operators. These disclosures are necessary in order for us to establish and maintain your account.   
With your consent, E*TRADE may disclose your personal information to other third parties who have an alliance with E*TRADE. If such alliances are entered into by E*TRADE, we will seek your consent prior to personal information about you being disclosed.   
* **ANZ E*TRADE Customers**  
If you are a ANZ E*TRADE customer, please note that E*TRADE is obliged under the terms and conditions which apply to your account to disclose personal information about you to ANZ. You agree to comply with these terms and conditions when you open a ANZ E*TRADE account.   
* **Outsourcing**  
Personal information collected by E*TRADE may be disclosed to third parties to whom E*TRADE contracts out specialised functions (eg IT systems support, share registry services or mail house functions). If E*TRADE does disclose personal information to third party contractors under outsourcing or contracting arrangements, E*TRADE takes reasonable steps to ensure that those third parties: 

    * comply with the NPPs when they handle your personal information; and 
    * are authorised only to use personal information in order to provide the services or to perform the functions required by E*TRADE. 

* **Disclosures required or permitted by law**  
Otherwise, E*TRADE will only disclose personal information if you consent, or if this is required by law or otherwise permitted under the Privacy Act. E*TRADE does not sell, rent or trade personal information about you to or with third parties.   
Back to Top  
**4\. Security of Personal Information**  
E*TRADE takes reasonable steps to ensure the security of your personal information from such risks as unauthorised access, loss or misuse.   
* **Online security**  
All information transmitted to the E*TRADE website is stored securely (to the extent possible using existing technology). When you are trading online, your security is protected through your use of a User ID and a secure site Log On password. A Trading password must also be entered each time you place an order to buy or sell. When accessing or initiating your transactions over the Internet, all communications with E*TRADE are secured through user authentication and 128-bit enabled data encryption. To ensure ongoing security, we encourage customers to change their password regularly.   
* **“Offline” security**  
We utilise “state–of–the–art” technology and systems to prevent unauthorised access to the information we hold.   
Our IT systems are password restricted and comply with relevant security standards. Personal information provided to us in “hard copy” written form is usually imaged and stored electronically in our secure database (this enables the paper originals to be destroyed). If personal information is held in paper files prior to imaging, it is stored in locked compactuses or filing cabinets. In all cases, access to the personal information we hold about you is restricted to authorised personnel. We take steps to ensure that our staff understand that they must protect your privacy.   
Back to Top  
**5\. Access and Correction**  
* **Access**  
  
If you are a customer, you already have the right to access your account information at any time, simply by logging into the website. However, you should be aware that there are now new rights of access to personal information under the Privacy Act.   
  
Under NPP6, you have the right to request access to the personal information which E*TRADE holds about you (although there are some exceptions to this). You also have the right to ask us to update or correct your personal information when it is inaccurate, incomplete or out of date.   
  
If you wish to exercise your right under the Privacy Act to seek access to the personal information that E*TRADE holds about you, we ask that you contact E*TRADE, using the contact details set out in clause 8 of this Privacy Policy.   
  
To summarise, in the first instance, E*TRADE will generally provide you with a summary of the information we hold about you. We will assume (unless you tell us otherwise) that your request relates to our current records about you. These current records will include personal information about you which is included in our databases and in paper files (i.e. where the relevant documents have not yet been imaged), and which we may use on a day-to-day basis.   
  
To provide you with access to your personal information, E*TRADE will ordinarily provide you with a copy of the relevant personal information (ordinarily, a print-out from a database or a photocopy of personal information recorded only in paper form). If personal information about you (for example, your name and address) is duplicated across difference databases or paper files, we will generally only provide you with one printout of this information, rather than multiple printouts. E*TRADE will not charge you for the cost of providing this type of access to these current records. If the personal information we collected about you has been de-identified such that we can no longer identify this information as being about you, you will not be given access to the de-identified information.   
  
Generally, E*TRADE will endeavour to acknowledge your request for access within 14 days, and to provide you with access within 30 days of the date of receipt of your request.   
  
For legal and administrative reasons, E*TRADE may also store records containing personal information in its archives. These archives include the images of the hard copy documents described at clause 4 above. You may seek access to these records held by E*TRADE which are not current records, but if you do, please be aware that it may take time to locate these records and we may not be able to respond to your request within 30 days of its receipt by us. Also, in these circumstances we may charge you for the cost of providing access.   
  
Please be aware that if the relevant personal information was collected before 21 December 2001, E*TRADE will only provide you with access in accordance with section 16C of the _Privacy Act_ 1988\. Section 16C states that access must only be provided to personal information collected before 21 December 2001 if we use and disclose that information after that date, and that providing access would not cause an unreasonable administrative burden or unreasonable expense.   
  
E*TRADE’s Privacy Officer will contact you to discuss how we will handle your request for access to non-current records.   
  
* **Correction**  
  
After we have provided you with access, if you are of the view that the personal information we hold about you is not accurate, complete or up to date, please let our Privacy Officer know. Please use the contact details set out at clause 7 below.   
Back to Top  
**6\. Online Privacy Issues**  
* **Online collection of personal and non-personal information**  
As outlined in the introduction to this policy, E*TRADE may collect personal information through our website. For example, if you ask us to send you an account opening kit by mail, we will collect your name, postal and email addresses, and telephone number. In addition, there are some services we only offer online, such as applications for access to managed funds and applications for margin lending services.   
E*TRADE may collect non–personal information from you by your use of the website. For example, we might track information about the date and time you access our site, the type of web browser you use, and the website from which you connected to our site. Generally, we do not collect information which personally identifies you. Rather, this information is collected in an aggregate form, e.g. the number of users using different types of web browsers. E*TRADE does not match any personal information we have collected about you with the anonymous navigation and other non-personal information which we collect when you visit our website.   
* **Use of information collected online**  
Generally, E*TRADE uses and discloses personal information collected online in the same way as it uses and discloses information collected offline. If we need to disclose personal information about you which we collect online, we will make this clear in the relevant online application form.   
* **Links to other websites**  
Sometimes our website contains links to third party websites for your convenience and information. When you access a non-E*TRADE website, please understand that E*TRADE is not responsible for the privacy practices of that site. We suggest that you review the privacy policies of each site you visit.   
Back to Top  
**7\. Business Contact Information**  
Sometimes E*TRADE will need to collect personal information about individuals who are not customers. This will usually arise where we collect the name and business contact details of a person who is the contact in a government agency or company with which we deal, such as a stockbroker or financial adviser. E*TRADE’s policy is to only use personal information collected from a non-customer for the main business purpose for which it was collected.   
Back to Top  
**8\. How to Contact E*TRADE**  
The E*TRADE Privacy Policy may change from time to time. The E*TRADE Privacy Policy will be made available to anyone who requests it, whether at our offices or through our website.   
If you have any questions or comments about the E*TRADE Privacy Policy, or if you wish to make a complaint about how E*TRADE has handled personal information about you, please contact E*TRADE:   
by telephone on 1300 658 355 between 8 am to 7 pm Monday to Friday; or   
by facsimile to (02) 9241 7954; or   
by email to privacy@etrade.com.au; or   
by letter to:  |   |  | The Privacy Officer  
---  
E*TRADE Australia   
Reply Paid 1346   
Royal Exchange NSW 1224  
Australia  
Back to Top  
**9\. Changes to this Privacy Policy and Additional Information**  
We strive to comply with the NPPs, and we intend to comply with any industry privacy codes as and when they are developed. If further privacy legislation and/or self-regulatory codes are introduced, or our Privacy Policy is updated, E*TRADE will summarise any modifications or enhancements in this section. Our Privacy Policy was last updated on 17 December 2001.   
For further information about privacy issues and the protection of privacy visit the Australian Federal Privacy Commissioner’s website at [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/)
